# PRASANTH JANARDHANAN

**Product Development Specialist** 

prasanthmj@gmail.com | +91 9845422369 | https://prasanthmj.github.io/ | linkedin.com/in/prasanthmj/

# Summary

15+ years of hands-on software product development experience. Certified Professional Scrum Product Owner. Hands-on full stack coding experience - Go (golang), Typescript, React. Experience working with customers gathering user stories, planning product roadmaps, and delivering value following agile methods.

### **FUNCTIONAL EXPERTISE**

- Agile and Scrum
- User story mapping
- MVP and Product Roadmap Planning
- Continuous user feedback analysis
- Coding: Go, Typescript, React
- Devops: Kubernetes, Terraform, AWS

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Simfatic Solutions,

simfatic.com

March 2009 - till date

Develops Software products for Process automation and workflow management

### **Senior Technical Manager**

- Helped develop a work management product for a telecom tower construction company that included live streaming from multiple work sites.
- Worked with Software teams to implement user stories delivering the best value to the target customers
- Managed integrating a smart support system right into the product that eventually helped reduce on-field errors users face.

### Electronics For Imaging, Inc,

https://www.efi.com

April 2004 – January 2009

Electronics for Imaging (Nasdaq: EFII) builds software products for large scale printing and publishing businesses.

#### **Associate Architect**

- Successfully designed and implemented a method to process very large PDF or PS files with more than 4GB in size with limited memory usage
- Worked with different product teams and external vendors to plan, design and implement
  an integration platform using an industry standard known as JDF ( cip4.org ). This integrated
  more than 4 separate information systems in different platforms as well as embedded
  systems and devices all working together in an automated manner.
- Worked on porting a Windows only desktop product to linux and mac

• Started a refactoring initiative of an older codebase adding unit tests, bringing in platform portability, better maintenance benefits.

#### **LG Software India**

[http://www.lgsoftindia.com/]

October 2002 – April 2004 The software development division of LG

### **System Analyst**

Working on Software products - embedded as well as tools for the electrical/electronic equipments

- Implemented a video player for the MMS clients in LG's feature phones.
- Lead the development of a product for estimating the load of HVAC (Air conditioning for large buildings) and generating quotations.

### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science**

1994-1998, Mahatma Gandhi University, Kottayam India.

Professional Scrum Product Owner, Scrum.org, 2022



### **OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS**

Open source projects that I maintain

### qUP

https://github.com/prasanthmi/qup

qUP is a background task processor with persistence support written in Go. It uses BadgerDb for persistence.

#### Chimes

https://github.com/prasanthmj/chimes

A JWT authentication library in TypeScript

### **OneCluster**

https://github.com/prasanthmj/onecluster

A Terraform/Ansible project to build Kubernetes infrastructure on Hetzner cloud

# **LANGUAGES**

• English, Fluent